A Guide to the Preston Family (Charles Peale Didier Collection) Papers, 1747-1897
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
- John Preston (1764-1827) Papers, 1780-1830, n.d.
  - Whitley Preston to [his father], Gen. John Preston in Richmond; Concerns a tract of land in Cabell County which Whitley suggests be resurveyed; Cabell County, January 8, 1816 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Received of John Preston, a sum for tuition for his daughter; Signed J. A. Oswald; Richmond, January 1816 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Francis Preston to "Dear Brother," Gen. John Preston, in Richmond; Concerns elections in Botetourt and Montgomery Counties; Fincastle, April 10, 1816 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Received of John Preston, $1000 for 50 bank shares; Signed B. Peyton [?], December 11, 1816 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Dr. J. Augustus Smith to John Preston in Richmond; Informs Preston of the poor conduct of his son at college; William and Mary College, December 25, 1816 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - John Preston to Dr. Augustus Smith [at the College of William and Mary]; Reply to Smith's letter of 25 December; Draft; Richmond, December 27, 1816 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - David French to Gen. John Preston in Richmond; Reports on French's arrival at Barboursville and his efforts to engage a surveyor; land deals in Ohio; Barboursville, February 8, 1817 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Randolph Ross to Gen. John Preston; Refers to Whitley Preston's visit to Havana; business matters; a trip to Philadelphia and Washington; Lexington, March 7, 1817 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Promissory note of Joshua Brotherhood to Gen. John Preston for 6000 acres of land warrants; Signed Gordon Cloyd, October 30, 1817 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Bill of goods bought from Wilson & Drew by Mr. John Preston; Items purchased between December 1814-July 1816; Account settled, August 1817 (Box 2, Folder 32a)
  - G. Peyton to [John Preston?]; Concerns rumors of land speculation involving the Treasurer of Virginia, Preston; Christiansburg, November 7, 1817 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Account of cattle taken to the range and/or bought, 1817. Signed Tilgh. H. West; Horseshoe, December 10, 1817 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - James McDowell to [his brother-in-law], Gen. John Preston; Letter of introduction for Hiram Jennings, a prospective overseer for Preston's plantation; Cherry Grove, December 28, 1817 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - "Articles given to the Negroes at the Horseshoe;" Lists articles of clothing given to slaves, December 1817 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Account of Gen. Preston with Charles [Purcell?], February 25, 1818 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Received of Mr. Preston, payment for pantaloons; Signed John Curry, April 18, 1818 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Received of Gen. Preston, payment for one great coat; Signed P. Shipard; Richmond, November 16, 1818 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - William Radford to [his brother-in-law], Gen. John Preston; Informs Preston that Radford will become president of the Farmers Bank in Lynchburg; requests that his name be withdrawn as a candidate for director of the Bank of Virginia; Lynchburg, December 20, 1818 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - William Norwell to John Brockenbrough in Richmond; Concerns choice of directors for the Bank of Virginia; Lynchburg, December 24, 1818 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Mary P. Lewis to "Dear Brother," Gen. John Preston; Requests legal advice on the acquisition of a piece of property; Sweet Springs, February 17, 1819 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Received of John Preston, payment for bank stock; Signed Carter B. Page. Richmond, June 19, 1819 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Promissory note of James G. Swann to John Preston, January 20, 1820 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Sarah P. Preston to "Dear Father," Gen. John Preston; Concerns school and vacation activities, family affairs; Cherry Grove, May 8, 1820 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - John Hammet to Gen. John Preston at Greenfield; Reports on affairs at Horseshoe Bottom; Horseshoe Bottom, June 4, 1820 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - George Munford to John B. Preston at Little Creek, Goochland County; Concerns the death of "Grandmama," who died at "Uncle William's" (William Radford);l Richmond, August 18, 1820 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Gordon Cloyd to Gen. John Preston in Richmond; Inquiries about whether Horseshoe is still for sale; Springfield, January 22, 1821 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Notification that John Preston and James P. Preston, as defendants in a court case, need to appear in court; Copy signed J. Robertson, Attorney General, June 20, 1821 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Nathaniel Hart to Gen. John Preston near Fincastle, Botetourt County; Concerns property of Preston's which has apparently been taken up by someone else; Spring Hill, [Kentucky], June 20, 1821 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Gen. Gordon Cloyd to Gen. John Preston; Concerns sale of steers and oxen; pasture land; Springfield, September 22, 1821 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Lists of directors for the Virginia Bank. [Ballots?]; Four sheets; one dated, January 23, 1823 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Nathaniel Hart to Gen. John Preston in Fincastle; Concerns a court settlement in favor of Preston which will probably be paid with a tract of land; Spring Hill, [Kentucky], April 23, 1824 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Broadside advertising land previously belonging Gen. John Preston in Giles, Cabell, and Kanawha counties for sale, October 30, 1824 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Transcriptions of several legal documents (on one sheet), including custody papers and power of attorney made out to John Preston by Peter McConnell Barren County, Kentucky, November 29, 1830 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - E[lizabeth] Madison to "Dear Brother," Gen. John Preston; Requests intercession of John on a business matter and three bushels of hemp seed (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Joseph Fagg to Gen. John Preston at Greenfield, Botetourt County; Concerns employment as an overseer (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Memorandum dealing with land entries in Kentucky for John Preston and Francis Preston (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Draft of a description of an unidentified woman; Signed J. Preston on verso (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Papers Relating to the John Preston Family, 1811-1833, n.d.
  - Whitley Preston, Grammar exercise, October 5, 1811 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Jacob [Rudisk?] to William Preston; Refers to hiring Mat again, December 25, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Thomas W. Ligon to William M. Radford in Liberty, Virginia; Discusses college life at Yale, New Haven, Connecticut, February 18, 1832 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - George Clark to William Radford in Lynchburg; Concerns land affairs in Kentucky, Lexington, June 8, 1833 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Elizabeth M. Preston to "My dear Brother," William W. R. Preston, at Falling Spring Valley, Bath County; Concerns family matters; Elizabeth and her sister Susanna will be attending school in Richmond (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Papers from Other Families, 1756-1897, n.d.
  - Land grant to Tobias Smith, 330 acres in Augusta County; Signed Robert Dinwiddie, March 10, 1756 (Oversize 1)
  - Account of Col. John Buchanan [with William McClenahan?]; Signed by McClenahan, November 20, 1766 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Accounts of Col. Breckinridge, 1767-1973; Lists accounts with various persons (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Land grant to Joseph Jenkins, 58 acres in Augusta County; Signed [Lord] Botetourt, May 12, 1770 (Oversize 1)
  - Certificate attesting the right of Thomas Page to hold 400 acres of property in Montgomery County; Signed Jos. Cabell, N. Cabell, Gabl. Penn, September 10, 1782 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Received of James Boyle, payment for a survey; Signed James Desor, March 18, 1789 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Note concerning land holdings of John Breckenridge to be surveyed; Signed David Robinson and John Love,, April 30, 178[9?] (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Agreement for harvesting a wheat crop by William Burr; Signed Chris Champ, July 8, 1791 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Received of William Thompson, rations for the Wythe Rangers; Signed James [McGaruth?], 1791 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Received from Messrs. McMurdo and Fisher, a sum resulting from a lawsuit against John Mayo by William Mayo; Signed Ben Sheppard, March 10, 1802. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Broadside, "Sketch of the Actions fought at San Pascal in Upper California between the Americans and Mexicans, Dec. 6th & 7th, 1846" (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Octavia [Radford?] to her sister-in-law, "Dear Sister Susan" [Susanna Smith Preston Radford]; Refers to Octavia's new-born son and other family members; Near Lynchburg,, June 21, 1852 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - John A. Shearer to William B. Radford and Henry Bowyer, in Amsterdam, Botetourt County; Requests information on J. M. Humphreys, a prospective principal of Shearer's boys academy; Spout[?] Spring, Appomattox County, June 1, 1857 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - A. G. Preston to [his wife] "My Dear Alice;" Speaks of his illness; Buchanan, March 9, 1897 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Account of Col. John Buchanan (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - List of repairs to be made to the Polygon, room by room; "Chris Tompkins" on back (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Accounts [for warrants?] totaling $19,240.00 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Draft of a letter from [?] to [?], referring to seeing Mr. [R.?] Preston in Williamsburg; land dealings; "Gran Smith" on top of first page (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Draft of a letter from [?] to "My Dear Agatha," writes of Mrs. Preston, who is dying (Box 3, Folder 7)